









Backend software engineer with three years of experience developing scalable microservices for e-commerce and fintech sectors utilizing Java, Python, and Golang. Achievements include leading a successful migration project at Walmart that resolved critical vulnerabilities without downtime andreducing operational costs by 30%. Promoted to SDE III within two years of initial hire at PayU, demonstrating rapid professional growth and impact within fast-paced environments.

## **EXPERIENCE**

WALMART (NRT - Data Venture) | SDE-III | JAVA, SPRING BOOT, KAFKA Jun, 2024 - Current | Bangalore

- → Skills and Platforms: Java, Kafka, PostgreSQL, Azure Cosmos DB, Spring Boot 3, Grafana.
- → Led a critical migration project to upgrade system to **Spring Boot 3** and **Java 17**, addressing and resolving critical and high vulnerabilities in the code. Overcame challenges such as backward compatibility, library deprecation issues, and dependency management to ensure a smooth transition with no service downtime.
- → Revamped all NRT application controllers using a design-first approach with OpenAPI Specification, reducing integration overhead by 30%.

GOOD CREATOR CO. (GCC SaaS Social Media Analytics Platform) | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | Python, Java, Golang, Clickhouse, PostgreSQL

Feb 2023 - May 2024 | Bangalore

- → Skills and Platforms: Java, Python, Golang, RabbitMQ, Postgres, Clickhouse, Airflow, DBT, Spring Boot, AWS.
- → Optimized API response times by 25% and reduced operational costs by 30% through platform development and optimization.
- → Drove user engagement by 10% by developing real-time social media insights
- → Built a high-performance logging system using Python, Golang, and RabbitMQ, cutting log retrieval times by 66%.
- → Designed an asynchronous data processing system handling 10 million daily data points for real-time insights.
- → Automated content filtering and elevated data processing speed by 50%.
- → Created an efficient asset upload system on AWS S3, processing 8 million images daily while minimizing costs.
- → Crafted and streamlined ETL data pipelines (Apache Airflow) for batch data ingestion for scraping and the data marts updates, cutting data latency by 50%.

PAYU (API Lending) | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | JAVA, PYTHON, SPRINGBOOT, DJANGO, POSTGRESQL Jul 2022 - Feb 2023 | Bangalore

- → Skills and Platforms: Java, Python, RabbitMQ, Postgresql, Django, Spring Boot, AWS.
- → Scaled business operations by 40% by enabling users to access loans from multiple sources after disbursal.
- → Mitigated loan disbursal journey issues from 4.6% to under 0.3% through new partner onboarding and process optimization.
- → Accelerated API responsiveness, leading to a decrease in loan disbursal journey TAT from 3.2 minutes to 1.1 minutes. Using Java and spring boot.

PAYU (API Lending) | Software Engineer Intern | Java, Python, Springboot, Django, Postgresql, AWS

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022 | Bangalore

- → Improved code readability, maintainability, and performance through refactoring the LOS in Java, resulting in an 83% unit test coverage (up from 30%) and reduced production bugs.
- → Automated code quality checks and static analysis by integrating SonarQube and GitHub Actions, boosting code coverage by 20%.
- → Implemented Flyway DB migrations, reducing deployment errors by 90% and improving release frequency by 2x.

## SKILLS

### **PROGRAMMING**

Java • Python • C++ • C • Golang • Data Structures and Algorithm

#### BACKEND FRAMEWORK

Spring Boot 3 • Hibernate • Django • FastAPI

#### DATABASE

PostgreSQL, MySQL (RDBMS) • Azure Cosmos DB • ClickHouse (Data Warehouse)

#### **TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS**

RabbitMQ • Redis • Apache Airflow • Git • GitHub • DBT • ETL • Kafka • Docker • Ansible • Jenkins • ELK Stack • AWS Cloud • Grafana • Prometheus

# **EDUCATION**

## IIIT BANGALORE

M.Tech - Computer Science and ENGINEERING Aug 2020 - Jul 2022 | Bangalore

#### **SKIT JAIPUR**

B.Tech - Computer Science AND ENGINEERING Aug 2015 - May 2019 | Jaipur

#### ACHIEVEMENTS

- → Secured an AIR 1343 in GATE 2020 (Score: 659).
- → Promoted diversity and inclusion in the Gender Cell at IIIT-B.
- → Event Manager, Infinite Cultural Fest, IIIT-B.
- → Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation.
- → Red Hat Certified System Administrator.
- → Taught CS-816 Software Production Engineering at IIIT-B as a **Teaching** Assistant.